Grace Hartigan Papers
Grace Hartigan Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - General correspondence-subject files
    - Cohen, Hallie, 1972-1982 (Box 8)
    - Cohen, Murray, See Genesis Galleries (New York, New York)
    - Colby, Joy, 1969-1982 (Box 8)
    - Colby, Sarah, 1980; undated (Box 8)
    - College Art Association of America, 1982-1983 (Box 8)
    - College of Saint Rose (Albany, New York), 1989 (Box 8)
    - Collings, Gerald, undated (Box 8)
    - Compton, Cher, 2000-2001 (Box 8)
    - Conceptual Glass Design (Baltimore, Maryland), 1983-1984 (Box 8)
    - Concordia University (Montreal), 1986-1987 (Box 8)
    - Connolly, Karl, 1994; undated (Box 8)
    - Connor, Colin, 1965-1976; undated (Box 8)
    - Contemporary Arts Museum (Houston, Texas), 1982-2000 (Box 8)
    - Cooke, George and Eleanor, 1962-1964; undated (Box 9)
    - Cooper Union for the Advancement of Science and Art (New York, New York), 1980; 1986 (Box 9)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art (Washington, D.C.), 1960; 1975-1976,; 1996-1997 (Box 9)
    - Cornell University (Ithaca, New York), 1981 (Box 9)
    - Correa, Federico, 1988-2003; undated (Box 9)
    - Corrin, Nicholas, 1991; 1993 (Box 9)
    - Cotter, Jacqueline, 1982 (Box 9)
    - Coulter, Vera (Mrs. Stanley), 1958 (Box 9)
    - Coyer, Max, 1987-1988 (Box 9)
    - Cranbrook Academy of Art (Bloomfield Hills, Michigan), 1981-1987 (Box 9)
    - Crase, Douglas, 2001 (Box 9)
    - Crow, Martha, 1978-1979 (Box 9)
    - Culpepper, Winston, 1974-2004; undated (Box 9)
    - The Cummer Museum of Art and Gardens (Jacksonville, Florida), 2003 (Box 9)
    - Cunliffe, Betty, 1990; 1995 (Box 9)
    - Cutter, Cynthia, 1993 (Box 9)
    - D, 1 folder (Box 9)
    - Dalsheimer, George, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Damen, Jessica, 1998-2003; undated; includes original watercolor (Box 9)
    - Daniels, Edwin (Ned), 1979-1980 (Box 9)
    - Dann, Elonzo, 2001-2003 (Box 9)
    - David Anderson Gallery (New York, New York), 1987 (Box 9)
    - Davis Museum and Cultural Center, See Wellesley College Museums (Wellesley, Massachusetts)
    - Davis, Jack, 1976-1977 (Box 9)
    - Davis, Mary Anne and Jim, 1996; undated (Box 9)
    - Davis, Turner G., undated (Box 9)
    - De Chassey, Eric, 1990 (Box 9)
    - De Kooning, Elaine, 1977-1987; undated; includes memorial notices, tribute notices, Hartigan's notes for tribute to her (Box 9)
    - De Nagy, Tibor, See Tibor de Nagy Gallery (New York, New York); Memorabilia: Photographs: Personal photographs: Grace Hartigan with others
    - Dean, Charles, 1998-2002 (Box 9)
    - "Dee-Dee", 1998-2001; undated (Box 9)
    - Delaware Art Museum (Wilmington, Delaware), 1971; 1987-2003,; undated (Box 9)
    - Dennis, Emily, 1955-1962; undated; includes brief essay on GH (Box 9)
    - Detroit Institute of Arts, 1968-1983 (Box 9)
    - Dickinson College (Carlisle, Pennsylvania), 1998-2003; undated; includes proof of book, Painting Art History, with chronology and GH interview, and exhibit catalog (Box 9)
    - Dickson, Deborah, 1991 (Box 10)
    - Diggory, Terence, 1987-2003; includes ms of Diggory's monograph on Frank O'Hara and GH, also catalog essay for Skidmore College exhibit; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Ding, Jenny (Xiaoqing), 2003; includes photos of her work (Box 10)
    - Diocese of Connecticut (Episcopal), 1969; includes annulment inquiry re. GH's third husband, Robert G. Keene (Box 10)
    - Donnelly, Judith Mazur, 1967-1968; undated (Box 10)
    - Dorsey, John, 1981; 1992 (Box 10)
    - Doubleday, 1991-1992 (Box 10)
    - Drew University (Madison, New Jersey), 1990-1991 (Box 10)
    - Drucker, Ruth, 1983 (Box 10)
    - Duncan, Jeff, 1979-1987 (Box 10)
    - Dutterer, William (Bill), 1972-2003; undated (Box 10)
    - E, 1 folder (Box 10)
    - Ebersole, Susan, 1987-1995 (Box 10)
    - Economoz, Nancy, 1965-1966; 1977,; undated (Box 10)
    - Edelson, Brenda, 1989 (Box 10)
    - Edris, Anne, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
    - Edward Tyler Nahem Gallery (New York, New York), 1990-1991; 2000 (Box 10)
    - Edwards, Ron, 1984-1985; undated (Box 10)
    - Effra Gallery (Charlotte Harbor, Florida), 1970-1973; undated; includes details of canvas stretching (Box 10)
    - Elzea, Ruth Miller, Rowland and Jessica, 1972-1988; undated (Box 10)
    - Embry, Norris, 1978-1979 (Box 10)
    - Emergency Cultural Government, 1970 (Box 10)
    - Enyart, Mary, 1971-1972 (Box 10)
    - The Equitable Trust Company, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Esman, Rosa M., See Rosa Esman Gallery (New York, New York)
    - Evangeline, Margaret, 2000; 2003 (Box 10)
    - Evans, Mary Page, 1981-2000; undated (Box 11)
    - Evans, [Mary] Page (daughter of Mary Page Evans), 1993-1994 (Box 11)
    - Evans, Thomas B. Jr. (Congressman), 1979; 1997 (Box 11)
    - F, 1 folder (Box 11)
    - Fabric Workshop (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Fastov Galleries (Washington, D.C.), 1988; includes photo of forged GH painting (Box 11)
    - Father Martin's Ashley at Oakington (Aberdeen, Maryland), 1983-2000 (Box 11)
    - Federico, Salvatore, 1975; 1991 (Box 11)
    - Feibes and Schmitt, Architects, 1994 (Box 11)
    - Feist, Harold, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Feminist Art Program, See California Institute of the Arts Feminist Art Program
    - Ferrer, Rafael, 1980; 2000 (Box 11)
    - Fetteray, Susan, 1978-1981; undated (Box 11)
    - Fiterman, Dolly, 1983-2000 (Box 11)
    - Fitzhugh, Jane, 1989; 1991,; undated (Box 11)
    - Flack, Audrey, 1979; 1998 (Box 11)
    - [Richard] Florsheim Art Fund, 1995; 2001 (Box 11)
    - Foard, Philip (Foard, Gisriel, O'Brien & Ward LLC), 2002 (Box 11)
    - Fogg, Richard, 1986-1999; undated (Box 11)
    - Folger, Walt and Dotty, 1966-1968; undated (Box 11)
    - Ford Foundation, 1959 (Box 11)
    - Forsell, Jack, 1977; undated (Box 11)
    - Fort Wayne Museum of Art (Fort Wayne, Indiana), 1980-1981 (Box 11)
    - Fort Wright College of the Holy Names (Spokane, Washington), 1971 (Box 11)
    - Foster, Sally, 1976; 1982,; undated (Box 11)
    - Foster, Stephen, 1992; 1998; includes proposal for Franz Kline retrospective (Box 11)
    - Foundation for Contemporary Performance Arts (New York, New York), 1993; 2001 (Box 11)
    - Fouts, David, 1995; undated (Box 11)
    - Fox, Steve, 1997-2001 (Box 11)
    - Frankenthaler, Helen and Motherwell, Robert, 1959-2000; undated; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Franklin Siden Gallery (Detroit, Michigan), 1967 (Box 12)
    - Frazier, Espi, 1995-2001; undated (Box 12)
    - Frost, Douglas, 1969; 1977 (Box 12)
    - Frostburg State College (Frostburg, Maryland), 1968-1969; 1980 (Box 12)
    - G, 1 folder (Box 12)
    - Galleria Minima (Milan), 1960 (Box 12)
    - Galleria Schneider (Rome), 1955 (Box 12)
    - The Gallery of Contemporary Art (Winston-Salem, North Carolina), 1970; includes slides (Box 12)
    - Gansz, David C.D., 1985-1992 (Box 12)
    - Garfin, Judy, 1986-1997; undated (Box 12)
    - Garman, Beverly, 1968 (Box 12)
    - Garmey, Stephanie, 1994-1999 (Box 12)
    - Gaugh, Harry F., 1983-1986 (Box 12)
    - Genesis Galleries (New York, New York), 1976-1980 (Box 12)
    - Georgia Museum of Art, 1969; 1992 (Box 12)
    - Gerber, Robert A., 1986; 1989 (Box 12)
    - Gibbar, Jennifer, 1975-1976 (Box 13)
    - Gibson, Jennifer, 1972-1976 (Box 13)
    - Gilbert, Edith, 1972; 1989 (Box 13)
    - Gillespie, Dorothy, 1983 (Box 13)
    - Gillet, Iva, 1996 (Box 13)
    - Glantzman, Sara, 1975 (Box 13)
    - [Bob] Glucksman Advertising, 1978 (Box 13)
    - God's Love We Deliver, 1989-1999 (Box 13)
    - Goings, Ralph, 1993 (Box 13)
    - Gomez Gallery (Baltimore, Maryland), 1992; 1995,; 1993 (Box 13)
    - Gooch, Brad, 1991; 1993 (Box 13)
    - Goucher College (Towson, Maryland), 1977-1996 (Box 13)
    - The Greenberg Gallery (St. Louis, Missouri), 1992 (Box 13)
    - Greenberg, Clement, 1954 (Box 13)
      See also Litwin, Harry
    - Greene, Steve, 1975-1985; undated (Box 13)
    - Gregg, Jon, 1994; 1996,; 2000 (Box 13)
    - Gres Gallery (Chicago, Illinois), 1961 (Box 13)
    - Gres Gallery (Washington, D.C.), See Perry, Beatrice
    - Grim, Patricia, 1979-1992; undated (Box 13)
    - Grimaldis Gallery (Baltimore, Maryland), 1979-2003; 2006; undated; includes sales data (Box 13)
    - Grosman, Tatyana, 1974 (Box 13)
    - Gross, Irwin M., See Detroit Institute of Arts (Detroit, Michigan)
    - Groulx, Adele, 1978-1981 (Box 13)
      See also Guilford College (Greensboro, North Carolina)
    - Gruenebaum Gallery (New York, New York), 1974-1988; undated (Box 13)
      See also Weissman, Julian and Karen
    - Guest, Barbara, 1953-1974; undated; includes original poems (Box 13)
    - Guggenheim, Peggy, 1959 (Box 13)
    - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1957; includes GH's application for Guggenheim fellowship (Box 13)
    - Guggenheim Museum (New York, New York), 1980-1990 (Box 13)
    - Guild Hall Museum (East Hampton, New York), 1981-2003 (Box 13)
    - Guilford College (Greensboro, North Carolina), 1978 (Box 13)
      See also Groulx, Adele
    - Gunderson, Karen, 1984-2003; undated (most) (Box 13)
    - Guston, Philip, 1962-1980; undated (Box 14)
    - H, 1 folder (Box 14)
    - Hall, Janice, 1972 (Box 14)
    - Hall, Lee, 1991-1993 (Box 14)
    - Hamburger, Sydney K., 1982-2003; undated (Box 14)
    - Hamilton Gallery (New York, New York), 1979-1983 (Box 14)
    - Hammatt, Zoë, 1992-1993 (Box 14)
    - Hankin, Ann and Michael, 1991; 1993,; 1999,; undated (Box 14)
    - Hansen, Waldemar, 1951-1953 (Box 14)
    - Harbourt, Craig, 1982-1983; undated (Box 14)
    - Harcus Gallery (Boston, Massachusetts), 1985 (Box 14)
    - Harding, Robert, 1987-1999 (Box 14)
    - Haring, Doug, 1998-2001 (Box 14)
    - Harmon, Hank, 1967; 1973 (Box 14)
    - Harrington, Chris, 1996; 1998 (Box 14)
    - Harvey, Emily, 1973; 1984 (Box 14)
    - Haussamen, Florence, 1962 (Box 14)
    - Hayes, Charles, See Hughlett, Bill
    - Head, Martha, 1991-1992; undated (Box 14)
    - Health Education Resource Organization (HERO), 1986 (Box 14)
    - Heilman, Philip D., 1996 (Box 14)
    - Henley, John, 1993-1994; undated (Box 14)
    - Hickey, JoAnn, 1995 (Box 14)
      See also Johns Hopkins Hospital, charity and donations
    - Hildebrandt, Bernhard, 1997; 1999,; undated (Box 14)
    - Hills, Patricia, 2000 (Box 14)
    - Hirshhorn Museum (Washington, D.C.), 1979-1981; 1999,; undated (Box 14)
    - Hobson, Ian, 1990-1995; undated (Box 14)
    - Hochschild-Kohn (Baltimore, Maryland), 1971-1972 (Box 14)
    - Hodges, Melinda, 1978-1980 (Box 14)
    - Hoffberger, LeRoy E., 1972 (Box 14)
    - Hoffberger graduate students, undated; get well cards signed by students (Box 14)
    - Hoffberger School, See Maryland Institute College of Art (MICA)
    - Hoffman, Hans, 1964-1966 (Box 15)
    - Holly Solomon Gallery (New York, New York), 1987-1989; includes 2 letters from GH (Box 15)
    - Holt, Elizabeth, 1978; 1983 (Box 15)
    - Hook, Scott, 1998-2003; undated (Box 15)
    - Hopkins, Genya C., 1999-2001 (Box 15)
    - Horton, Rick, 1984-1989; undated (Box 15)
    - House of Brata (New York, New York), See Brata Gallery (New York, New York)
    - Hsieh, Chase C., 1995 (Box 15)
    - Hubbard, Sandra and John, 1983-1984 (Box 15)
    - Hübuer, Otto and Kirsten, 1997; undated (Box 15)
    - Hudson Hills Press, 1989-2003; undated (Box 15)
    - Hudson River Editions, 1984-1991 (Box 15)
    - Hughlett, Bill, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Hummel, Ralph, 1989; undated (Box 15)
    - Humphrey, Ralph, 1959 (Box 15)
    - Hunter College (New York, New York), 1982-1983 (Box 15)
    - I, 1 folder (Box 15)
    - Illinois Wesleyan University (Bloomington, Illinois), 1971-1975 (Box 15)
    - Independent Curators Inc., 1984-1986 (Box 15)
    - Institute of Contemporary Art (University of Pennsylvania), 1986 (Box 15)
    - Institute of International Education (New York, New York), 1969-1970 (Box 15)
    - International Artist's Colony (Dunedin, New Zealand), 1990 (Box 15)
    - Irving Feldman Galleries (Southfield, Michigan), 1981-1982 (Box 15)
    - Isospin Two South, Inc. (Baltimore, Maryland), 1993 (Box 15)
    - J, 1 folder (Box 15)
    - Jackson, Martha, See Martha Jackson Gallery (New York, New York)
    - Jacobs, Phyllis, 1975 (Box 15)
    - Janowich, Ron, 1972 (Box 15)
    - Jeffers, Wendy, 1994-2003; includes GH's comments on Dorothy Miller (Box 15)
    - Joan Mitchell Foundation, See [Joan] Mitchell Foundation
    - Joans, Ted, 1959; includes poem "For Grace: Lines" (Box 15)
    - Johns Hopkins Hospital, charity and donations, 1980-1996 (Box 15)
    - Johns Hopkins Hospital, medical information, 1975; 1994,; 1998 (Box 15)
    - Johns, Jasper, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Johnson, Jamie, 1983-2003; undated (Box 15)
    - Johnson, Theresa, 2000; includes draft of GH's letter of recommendation (Box 15)
    - Julian Weissman Fine Art, See Weissman, Julian and Karen
    - K, 1 folder (Box 16)
    - Kamenetz, Rodger, 1981; includes poems (Box 16)
    - Kansas City Art Institute (Kansas City, Missouri), 1979 (Box 16)
    - Kansas City Artists Coalition, 1979; includes interview with GH (Box 16)
    - Kaputsos, Chrysanthea, 1987-1988; includes poems (Box 16)
    - Karlen, Megan, 1988; undated (Box 16)
    - Kasle, Gertrude and Leonard, 1967-1997; undated; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Kasle, Mercy and Leah, 1976-1991 (Box 16)
    - Kast, Sheilah, See Rosapepe, Jim and Sheilah Kast
    - Keene, Robert, See Robert Keene Gallery (Southampton, New York)
    - Keller, Jeffrey, 2000 (Box 16)
    - Kendall, Dina(h), 1965-1966; 1999 (Box 16)
    - Kent State University (Kent, Ohio), 1971; undated; includes GH print (Box 16)
    - Kernan, Nathan, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Kerns, Ed, 1978-2003; includes 2 original drawings by Kerns and GH's notes for letter of recommendation (Box 16)
    - Kimler, Wesley, 1994 (Box 16)
    - King-Hammond, Leslie, 1993-2001; undated (Box 16)
    - Kingsley, April, 1983-1990 (Box 16)
    - Kinnecone, Mary, 1996-2000 (Box 16)
    - Kinney, Ann and Gilbert, undated (Box 16)
    - Kline, Carl (nephew of Franz Kline), 1997; 1999 (Box 16)
    - Klitzke, Ted, 1977; 1995,; 1998 (Box 16)
    - Kootz Gallery (New York, New York), 1950 (Box 16)
    - Koplin Gallery (Santa Monica, California), 1990; includes show announcements for various artists (Box 16)
    - [Camillos] Kouros Gallery (Baltimore, Maryland), 1982-1992 (Box 16)
    - Kramer, Esta, 1978-1992; undated (Box 17)
    - L, 1 folder (Box 17)
    - La Perriere, Michelle, 1989-1999; includes handmade cards, collages (Box 17)
    - Labadie, Kevin, 1980-1984 (Box 17)
    - Lafayette College (Easton, Pennsylvania), 1981-1994 (Box 17)
    - Landau, Ellen G., 1977 (Box 17)
    - Langer, Sandra L., 1980 (Box 17)
    - Lanyon, E. Jean, 1979 (Box 17)
    - Lapcek, Barbara, undated (Box 17)
      See also Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture (Skowhegan, Maine)
    - Lapides, Allene, See Allene Lapides Gallery (Santa Fe, New Mexico)
    - Larrimore, Jo Ann, 2002 (Box 17)
    - Lattin, Vernon, See Brooklyn College (Brooklyn, New York)
    - Lawrence Oliver Gallery (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), 1982 (Box 17)
    - Lawrence, Lisa, 1977-1982 (Box 17)
    - Lazarus, Fred, See Maryland Institute College of Art (MICA) (Baltimore, Maryland)
    - Le Sueur, Joseph (companion of Frank O'Hara), 1959; 1977 (Box 17)
      See also O'Hara, Frank
    - Leake, Eugene, 1971-1994 (Box 17)
    - Lebish, Harriet, See Genesis Galleries (New York, New York)
    - Lehman, Arnold, 1983; 1991,; 1994,; undated; includes letter from GH (Box 17)
      See also Baltimore Museum of Art
    - Leslie, Alfred, 1953-1960 (Box 17)
      See also Memorabilia: Photographs: Personal photographs: Grace Hartigan with others; Memorabilia: Photographs: Personal photographs: Photos of others
    - Levy, Esther, 1980-1981 (Box 17)
    - Lewis, James, See Morgan State University (Baltimore, Maryland)
    - Liberatore, Sarah A. Mattis, 1994-1997 (Box 17)
    - Library of Congress, 1984-1985; includes poster for show on painting and poetry featuring GH and Frank O'Hara (Box 17)
    - Lieberman, Elissa, 2003 (Box 17)
    - Life (magazine), 1957; 1959 (Box 17)
    - Lindsay, Sally, See Bos, Sally Lindsay and John
    - Lindsley, James Eliott and Barbara, 1982-1984 (Box 17)
    - Linnan, Brenda, 1996; 2000,; undated (Box 17)
    - Lipman, Barbara, 1987; undated (Box 17)
    - Lisle, Laurie, 1986 (Box 17)
    - Litwin, Harry, 1978-1992; includes letter from Clement Greenberg to Litwin about GH and letter from GH to Clement Greenberg about Litwin (Box 17)
      See also Greenberg, Clement
    - "Liza, Bob, Anna and Henry", 1992; 1999,; undated (Box 17)
    - Lott, Lawrence, 1982-1990 (Box 17)
    - Lovett, Didi (Mrs. Robert S.), 1972-1973 (Box 17)
    - Loyola College in Maryland, 1972-1998 (Box 17)
    - Loyola Marymount University (Los Angeles, California), 1982-1984 (Box 17)
    - Lucic, Karen, 1999 (Box 17)
    - Lundquist, Sara, 1998; includes essay on Hartigan/Guest collaboration (Box 17)
    - Lurie, Sheldon, 1964-1967 (Box 17)
    - Lynch, Dee, 1997 (Box 17)
    - M, 1 folder (Box 17)
    - MacDowell Colony (Peterborough, New Hampshire), 1969 (Box 18)
    - MacLeod, Glen, 1987-1995; includes mss about GH's relationship with poet Wallace Stevens (Box 18)
    - Maddex, Alison, 1993-1994; undated (Box 18)
    - Mademoiselle (magazine), 1957-1959; includes draft of interview (Box 18)
    - Madoo, Bob, 1981 (Box 18)
    - Maggio, John, 1986-2002; includes copy of letter from GH (Box 18)
    - Maguire, Bob, 1993-1994 (Box 18)
    - Maguire, Maura, 1985-2003; undated (Box 18)
    - Maier Museum of Art (Lynchburg, Virginia), 1959; 1991 (Box 18)
    - Majerski, Raymond, 2002-2003 (Box 18)
    - Majorowitz, Roger, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Mann, John (Dr.), 1995-2001 (Box 18)
    - Marchant, Shani, 1982-1991; undated (Box 18)
    - Marcus, Marcia, 1957-2003? (Box 18)
    - Marino, Louise, 1966-1967; undated; Additional material in Oversize box 1 (Box 18)
    - Mark Rothko Foundation, See [Mark] Rothko Foundation
    - Markbreiter, Shari and Michael, 2000-2001; undated (Box 18)
    - Marks, Claude, 1978-1979; includes GH's notes for autobiographical sketch (Box 18)
    - Marquand Books (Seattle, Washington), 1994 (Box 18)
    - Martha Jackson Gallery (New York, New York), 1959-1973; undated; includes GH's notes on Martha for memorial service as well as dated documentation of a curious incident in which Ray Williams, an alleged mafioso, tried to sell some stolen GH paintings back to the gallery; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Maryland Art Place, 1983-1984 (Box 18)
    - Maryland Historical Society, 1975; 1992 (Box 18)
    - Maryland Institute College of Art (MICA), 1966-2003; undated; includes GH's letters to Fred Lazarus (director) and draft of MICA/Hoffberger description for website; 4 folders (Box 18)
      See also Meyerhoff, Jane and Robert
    - Maryland State Department of Education, 1988 (Box 19)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2002 (Box 19)
    - Matisse, Pierre (son of Henri Matisse), 1971 (Box 19)
    - Matter, Mercedes, 1956; 1973,; undated (Box 19)
    - Mattison, Robert Saltonstall, 1983-2001; undated; includes extensive draft material for Mattison's book on GH; 4 folders (Box 19)
      See also Hudson Hills Press; for typescript of diary entries from "Living for Art" see Writiings: Living for Art
    - Mattison, Carolyn (Mrs. Norman D.), 1990-1994; undated (Box 19)
    - Maynes, Bill, 1990; includes letter from GH (Box 19)
    - McAlee, Samée, 1990; 1995,; undated (Box 19)
    - McCarthy, David, 1996 (Box 19)
    - McGinnis, Lucille, 1957 (Box 19)
    - McGuinness, Daniel, 1997; includes copy of notes for lecture on GH and Frank O'Hara (Box 19)
    - McIntyre, David, 1983; 1992 (Box 19)
    - McNay Art Museum (San Antonio, Texas), 1976; 1988-1989 (Box 19)
    - McNeil, George, 1990-1994 (Box 19)
    - Mead Art Museum, See Amherst College (Mead Art Musem) (Amherst, Massachusetts)
    - Meagher, David, 1982-1983; 1988,; 1998 (Box 19)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, New York), 1983-1991 (Box 19)
    - Meyerhoff, Jane and Robert, 1962; 1964,; 1971,; 1972,; 1990,; 1995,; 2002,; undated (Box 20)
      See also Maryland Institute College of Art (MICA)
    - Meyerhoff, Marilyn, 1981 (Box 20)
    - Meyers, Doris, 1972-1973 (Box 20)
    - Meyerson, Ronnie, 1990 (Box 20)
    - Meza, Rosemary, 1995-1998; undated (Box 20)
    - Michael Rosenfeld Gallery (New York, New York), 2001 (Box 20)
    - Michener, James A., 1964 (Box 20)
    - [James A.] Michener Arts Center (Doylestown, Pennsylvania), 1988-1989 (Box 20)
    - Michigan State University, 2002-2003 (Box 20)
    - Michigan Water Color Society, 1973-1984 (Box 20)
    - Midwood (Germantown, New York), 1999 (Box 20)
    - Mikolowski, Ken and Ann, 1974-1976 (Box 20)
    - Mikulski, Barbara (Senator), 1978; 1992 (Box 20)
    - Millburn High School (Millburn, New Jersey), 1962 (Box 20)
    - Miller, Dorothy, 1976-1979 (Box 20)
      See also Jeffers, Wendy
    - Miller, Richard, 1954; undated (Box 20)
    - Miller, Robert, See Robert Miller Gallery (New York, New York)
    - Miller, Trace, 1986-1999; undated (Box 20)
    - Ming, Wendy, 1971-1973; undated (Box 20)
    - Minter, Lew, 1974; 1978,; 1982 (Box 20)
    - Mitchell, Joan, 1958; undated (Box 20)
      See also Robert Miller Gallery (New York, New York); Somers, John and Marion
    - [Joan] Mitchell Foundation, 1994-2003; includes meeting minutes, press releases, publicity (GH served on Board of Directors) (Box 20)
    - Mogavero, Michael, 1976; 1993,; undated (Box 20)
    - Mondale, Walter F., 1971; undated (Box 20)
    - Moody, Vearl Gil and Linda, 1984-1992 (Box 20)
    - Moore College of Art (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania), 1969 (Box 20)
    - Moore, Elizabeth, 1995 (Box 20)
    - Morgan State University (Baltimore, Maryland), 1990 (Box 20)
    - Morishita, Ryozo, 1975-2003 (Box 20)
    - Morris, Carol, 1972; 1989 (Box 20)
    - Morris, Kate, 1989-2000 (Box 20)
    - Mosely, Quentin, 1971-1972; undated (Box 20)
    - Moss, Tobey C., See Tobey C. Moss Gallery (Los Angeles, California)
    - Motherwell, Robert, See Frankenthaler, Helen and Motherwell, Robert
    - Mozley, Anita Ventura, 1992-1994; undated (Box 20)
    - Muhlbauer, Micki, 1988-1993 (Box 21)
    - Muhlert, Chris and Jan, 1979-1980 (Box 21)
    - Mullarkey, Maureen, 1987 (Box 21)
    - Mullin, Diane, 1993; includes dissertation prospectus (Box 21)
    - Munro, Eleanor, 1997; undated (Box 21)
    - Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute (Utica, New York), 1974 (Box 21)
    - Museum and Arts Magazine, 1990 (Box 21)
    - Museum of Contemporary Art (Los Angeles, California), 1992-1993; 1998 (Box 21)
    - Museum of Fine Arts (Boston, Massachusetts), 1984 (Box 21)
    - Museum of Modern Art (New York, New York), 1953-1999 (Box 21)
    - Myers, John Bernard, 1952-1962; 1981-1983,; 1987; includes GH's notes for memorial service (Box 21)
      See also Tibor de Nagy Gallery (New York, New York); Memorabilia: Photographs: Personal photographs: Grace Hartigan with others
    - N, 1 folder (Box 21)
    - Nahas, Dominique, 2001-2003 (Box 21)
    - Nahem, Edward Tyler, See Edward Tyler Nahem Gallery (New York, New York)
    - Nason, Thelma, 1975 (Box 21)
    - National Academy of Design (New York, New York), 1976-1988 (Box 21)
    - National Art Education Association, 1994 (Box 21)
    - National Association of Women Artists, 1986 (Box 21)
    - National Gallery of Art (Washington, D.C.), 1992-2001; undated (Box 21)
    - National Gallery of Canada (Ottawa), 1990 (Box 21)
    - National Museum of American Art, See Smithsonian Museum (Washington, D.C.)
    - National Museum of Women in the Arts (Washington, D.C.), 1990-2002 (Box 21)
    - National Organization for Women, 1975; 1981 (Box 21)
    - Neill, Christine, 1973-2001; undated (Box 21)
    - Nemser, Cindy, 1969-1974; 1990,; 1996,; undated (Box 21)
    - Neuberger Museum (Purchase, New York), 1989-2003; includes letter from GH, copies of reviews of 2001 show (Box 21)
    - New York Central Art Supply Co., 1974-1990 (Box 22)